(upbeat music)
- Hello English learners, welcome back.
We are here at EnglishPod,
my name is Marco.
- And I'm Erica.
- And today we're gonna be
bringing you a lesson about eggs.
- That's right.
And who knew there was so much
to talk about when we're talking eggs?
- Right, well, we always
have eggs for breakfast,
and there are many
ways of preparing them,
so we're gonna learn
what the different ways are.
- Yes, and we'll learn some of the
language that goes along with eggs.
- Okay.
We have three words that we wanna take
a look at before we listen to a dialogue,
so let's look at these
in vocabulary preview.
- vocabulary preview.
Our preview word for this
lesson is picky, picky, picky.
Picky.
So picky is an interesting adjective.
- Okay, so if a person is
picky, what does that mean?
- They're very hard to please.
- Okay, so if your boss is picky, and
you give him a report and maybe it has,
I don't know, a couple
of mistakes or something.
- Yeah, he'll say do it again,
change this, this, and this.
- Okay.
- So if you are picky, you
want everything to be perfect.
- Okay.
- And if there's one small thing
that's not, you won't be happy.
- Okay, so picky, interesting word.
Now our next word, yolk.
- Yolk.
- Y-o-l-k.
- So this word is actually
not in the dialogue.
It's not in the dialogue, but it's
important that you know, right?
- Okay, so if you have an egg,
the yellow part is called the yolk.
- Okay, and what about the other part?
- The white, the white.
- The white.
- Or also called the egg white, right?
- Yes.
- Egg white.
- Okay, so pretty simple,
yolk and egg white.
- Mm-hmm.
- Let's listen to our dialogue.
We are gonna be listening to a
couple who are having breakfast.
(upbeat music)
- Wow, Europe early today.
What's your breakfast?
- Well, I felt like baking,
so I made some muffins.
- Smells good.
I'll make some coffee.
Do you want me to make you some eggs?
- Sure, I'll take my sunny side off.
- Ew, I don't know how you
can eat your eggs like that.
Ever since I was small,
I've had eggs and soldiers.
- You know, my dad had scrambled
eggs every morning for 20 years.
It drove my mom crazy.
- You know what really drives me crazy?
When I asked her soft boiled eggs
and they overcook them so
they come out hard boiled.
How can you dip your
toast into a hard boiled egg?
- Here's so picky sometimes.
(upbeat music)
- Here you go honey, fried eggs.
- Dammit.
- I said sunny side up.
How many times do I have to tell you?
(upbeat music)
- Well, she is definitely very
picky and has a very bad temper.
- I know, I can't believe anyone
would get so angry over their breakfast.
- Yeah, yeah.
- But I guess it is the most
important meal of the day.
- Exactly.
- So we heard a couple of different
ways of describing how you prepare eggs.
So let's take a look at
that in language takeaway.
- Language takeaway.
- Okay, so our first preparation
method, my favorite, sunny side up.
- Okay, sunny side up, sunny side up.
Now this is interesting,
sunny like the sun, right?
- Exactly.
- So when you fry an egg, right?
And the yolk looks
like a little sun, right?
- Yeah, exactly.
- So why is it called sunny side up?
- I think because of what you just said,
it looks like the sun, but
you don't cook the yolk, right?
- Okay, yeah, the yolk is still yellow,
it's still a little bit liquid,
that's a little bit soft.
- Okay, because the
opposite would be a fried egg.
- Yes.
- And that's our second word.
- Fried egg, fried egg.
- So this you put the egg in the pan
and you cook it all the way through.
- All the way through.
- So the yolk is not liquid
anymore, becomes hard.
- Yes.
- Right?
- Exactly.
- Okay, a fried egg.
- Fried egg.
All right, so now let's take a
look at our next set of eggs.
- All right.
- Soft boiled egg.
- A soft boiled egg.
- Soft boiled.
- Okay, so to boil, you
put the egg in water.
- In boiling water.
- Yes, and make it cook.
- And make it cook.
So how long would you usually put it
in for to be soft boiled in three minutes?
Four minutes?
- Three minutes, yes.
- Okay, so you only cook
part of the egg, right?
- Right, the yolk, the yellow part, stays
a little bit wet, a little bit liquid.
- Uh-huh, okay.
So again, the opposite
would be a hard boiled egg.
- Hard boiled egg.
- Hard boiled.
- So hard boiled is when
you cook the entire egg again.
- Yes, so then it's hard, like a ball.
- The entire egg.
So with this soft boiled
and hard boiled eggs,
this takes us to our next
form, eggs and soldiers.
- Eggs and soldiers.
- Now this is really interesting.
I didn't really know about this before.
It kind of sounds like you're having eggs
with a group of soldiers from the army.
(laughing)
- Well, this is a very
British way of eating eggs.
So you have your soft boiled egg in
a cup, and you have a piece of toast.
But the toast is cut into long pieces.
- Okay.
- And then you take those pieces
and you dip them into the egg yolk.
- Oh.
- Delicious.
- It's good.
- Yeah.
Typical English way of eating eggs.
- Okay, so eggs and soldiers interesting.
And this takes us to our last form of egg
preparation and probably the most popular.
- Yes.
Scrambled eggs.
- Scrambled eggs.
- Take eggs, put them in a pan, and
then you just move them all over the place.
- Mix them all up.
- So the yellow, so the yolk
and the white are mixed together.
- Mix together.
- Mm-hmm.
- All right.
So we've looked at a
lot of egg preparation,
and now we can listen to our
dialogue for the second time,
and then we'll come back
and look at some phrases.
(upbeat music)
- Wow, you're up early today.
What's for breakfast?
- Well, I felt like baking,
so I made some muffins.
- Smells good.
I'll make some coffee.
Do you want me to make you some eggs?
- Sure, I'll take my sunny side up.
- Ew, I don't know how you
can eat your eggs like that.
Ever since I was small,
I've had eggs and soldiers.
- You know, my dad had scrambled
eggs every morning for 20 years.
It drove my mom crazy.
- You know what really drives me crazy?
When I asked for soft boiled eggs,
and they overcook them,
so they come out hard-boiled.
How can you dip your
toast into a hard-boiled egg?
- Mm-hmm, you're so picky sometimes.
Here you go, honey, fried eggs.
- Dammit, I said sunny side up.
How many times do I have to tell you?
(upbeat music)
- Interesting that the man in this
dialogue is the one doing the baking.
- Yeah, well, that's modern days.
I don't know, men are
learning how to cook, and yeah.
- A house has been.
- House has been, so yeah,
more popular these days.
- All right, well, since
this house has been,
felt like baking, I
think we should look at
this and one other
phrase in fluency builder.
- Okay, so great phrase.
He said, I felt like baking.
- I felt like baking.
So let's take a look at this.
He feels like, or he felt like in the past,
what does that mean when you feel like?
- You want to do it, you
have the desire to do it.
- Okay, and then to bake, and
now this verb is in the gerund form.
- That's right, the ING form.
- And that's the rule, right?
I feel like playing soccer.
- Right, I feel like eating lunch.
I felt like going to the movies.
That's the way you would say this.
You have the desire, you
feel like doing something.
- Exactly.
- Okay, very good.
And now let's take a
look at this second phrase.
Drives me crazy.
- Drives me crazy.
- All right, this is a
very descriptive phrase.
And I think if we listen to some examples,
it will help us understand the meaning.
- Example one.
- This music is driving
me crazy, turn it down.
- Example two.
- Don't leave garbage in my car.
It drives me crazy.
- Example three.
- Your mom is driving me crazy.
She keeps calling me.
- All right, so if
something drives you crazy.
- It makes you feel very angry or annoyed.
- Irritated.
- Yeah, frustrated.
- Okay, but it can also be positive, right?
Like that girl drives me crazy.
- As in you really,
really, really like her.
- Yeah.
- I don't know, it sounds
a little bit inappropriate.
- Really?
(laughing)
- I think it's okay, it
just drives me crazy.
- I think it's okay.
She's got me thinking, and she's got
me in the clouds or something like that.
- All right, well maybe
there's something about you
that I don't need to know, so I'll just
let you keep that thought to yourself.
- All right, well I'm just saying we
could use it in a positive form as well.
- Okay, okay.
(laughing)
- I'm just saying.
All right, so drives me crazy.
Really great phrase, and you can use it
in all of these different
situations like we heard.
So let's listen to our
dialogue for the last time,
and then we'll come back
and talk a little bit more.
(upbeat music)
(birds chirping)
- Wow, you're up early
today, what's for breakfast?
- Well, I felt like baking,
so I made some muffins.
- Smells good.
I'll make some coffee.
Do you want me to make you some eggs?
- Sure, I'll take my sunny side off.
- I don't know how you
can eat your eggs like that.
Ever since I was small,
I've had eggs and soldiers.
- You know, my dad had scrambled
eggs every morning for 20 years.
It drove my mom crazy.
- You know what really drives me crazy?
When I asked for soft boiled eggs,
and they overcook them so
they come out hard boiled.
How can you dip your
toast into a hard boiled egg?
- Here's so picky sometimes.
(upbeat music)
- Here you go honey, fried eggs.
- Damn it.
(upbeat music)
- I said sunny side up.
How many times do I have to tell you?
- Well, I think there are some people
who really, really love
eating eggs for breakfast,
and some people
who just can't stand it.
- Yeah, I don't know who, though.
I mean, who doesn't
like eggs in the morning?
- I know, I'm a big fan, right?
Eggs, bacon, toast.
- Yes, good stuff.
- Traditional American type breakfast.
- Now you were telling me that you
have some traditions when you eat eggs.
- I know, I think, I'm not
sure if this is just in my family,
but I think actually it might be
common with other people as well.
When you eat a soft
boiled or hard boiled egg,
you have to eat all of the
egg outside of the shell,
and then you have to break the
bottom of the shell after you finished.
- Why?
- So that the fairies who live
in your egg cup can come out.
(laughing)
- So it's kind of like a superstition.
- Yeah, I guess it is.
- That's the same.
- Yeah, so I don't know.
You guys, do you have any egg traditions
or any other crazy food stories like that?
- Well, for example, I was telling you
that when I prepare scrambled eggs,
sometimes I like to take some rice,
some rice that has already been cooked,
put it in the pan, and then
take some eggs, two eggs, put
it on top of the rice, and
scramble the rice with the eggs.
- Okay, for breakfast?
- Yeah, it could be for breakfast, yeah.
- A little bit, not like
a huge plate of rice,
or maybe at night, you
don't have anything to eat.
- Okay.
- Scrambled eggs with rice.
It's a poor man's food.
- All right, well, it's
also a quick man's food.
- Yeah, exactly.
So let us know if you guys
have any egg preparations
or any special egg recipes
or traditions that you practice.
- Visit our website
at englishpod.
com where you can leave all of
your comments and questions.
- Exactly, and as always, we are there
to answer them and solve any problems.
- Well, we're out of time for
today, but until next time, bye.
(upbeat music)